Andrew Eisenberg collection of East African commercial sound recordings AD.MC.035
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
- Series I: Private collector (anonymous) - 78's, circa 1930-1965; 8440; PP; 313 audio_recordings
  - Yaseen and King's Band, 12510
    - Yassen and King's Band: Zake, circa 1952-1961; 8840; 1 audio_recording 16.1 MB (Folder 283)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.758, A.M. 13. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:02.
  - Yaseen and Mimi, 12511
    - Yaseen & Mimi (Radio Singer): Kijana Mpenzi, 8622; 1 audio_recording 16.1 MB (Folder 284)
      Serial number: Columbia, EOM.19, CES. 10032. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as: Yaseen Mohamed, Yasseen Mohamed, Yaseen Tofaly. Duration: 3:02.
      Ki-Swahili; Columbia; Magic Notes Trade Mark
    - Yaseen & Mimi (Radio Singer): Muli Bwanchi, N/A; 8718; 1 audio_recording 15.3 MB (Folder 285)
      Serial number: Columbia, EOM.19, CES. 10027. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as: Yaseen Mohamed, Yasseen Mohamed, Yaseen Tofaly. Duration: 2:53.
    - Yaseen Mimi & Party: Hatuonani Kwanini, circa 1955-1965; 8607; 1 audio_recording 16.0 MB (Folder 286)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.2, CES 10104. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as: Yaseen Mohamed, Yasseen Mohamed, Yaseen Tofaly. Duration: 3:00.
    - Yaseen Mimi & Party: Mambo Africa, circa 1955-1965; 8666; 1 audio_recording 14.9 MB (Folder 287)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.2, CES 10103. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as: Yaseen Mohamed, Yasseen Mohamed, Yaseen Tofaly. Duration: 2:49.
    - Yaseen and Mimi (Radio Singers): Ladies Show, circa 1955-1965; 8648; 1 audio_recording 14.8 MB (Folder 288)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.151, AB 301. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as: Yaseen Mohamed, Yasseen Mohamed, Yaseen Tofaly. Duration: 2:47.
    - Yaseen & Mimi (Radio Singers): Mimi Nawe Mbali, circa 1955-1965; 8689; 1 audio_recording 14.4 MB (Folder 289)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.151, AB 304. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as: Yaseen Mohamed, Yasseen Mohamed, Yaseen Tofaly. Duration: 2:43.
    - Yaseen & Mimi (Radio Singers): Kisonge, circa 1955-1965; 8632; 1 audio_recording 15.8 MB (Folder 290)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.152, AB 302. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as: Yaseen Mohamed, Yasseen Mohamed, Yaseen Tofaly. Duration: 2:59.
    - Yaseen & Mimi (Radio Singers): Marehemu Mpenzi, circa 1955-1965; 8672; 1 audio_recording 15.8 MB (Folder 291)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.152, AB 303. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as: Yaseen Mohamed, Yasseen Mohamed, Yaseen Tofaly. Duration: 2:58.
    - Yaseen and Mimi (Radio Singers): Pipa, circa 1955-1965; 8779; 1 audio_recording 14.3 MB (Folder 292)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.351, A.B. 701. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as: Yaseen Mohamed, Yasseen Mohamed, Yaseen Tofaly. Duration: 2:42.
    - Yaseen and Mimi (Radio Singers): Wachawi, circa 1955-1965; 8821; 1 audio_recording 16.7 MB (Folder 293)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.351, A.B. 702. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as: Yaseen Mohamed, Yasseen Mohamed, Yaseen Tofaly. Duration: 3:08.
  - Yaseen Fara, 12500
    - Yaseen Fara: Mal El Gamil (Part 1), circa 1955-1965; 8663; 1 audio_recording 14.4 MB (Folder 294)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.358, A.B. 715. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as Yaseen Abdulla Farah. Duration: 2:43.
    - Yaseen Fara: Mal El Gamil (Part 2), circa 1955-1965; 8664; 1 audio_recording 15.0 MB (Folder 295)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.358, A.B. 716. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as Yaseen Abdulla Farah. Duration: 2:50.
  - Young India Band, 12435
    - (Young India Band) Miss Kiran & Pardesi: Fikisha Barua Na, circa 1935-1955; 8594; 1 audio_recording 16.4 MB (Folder 296)
      Serial number: Young India, T 752, SR.134. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:06.
    - (Young India Band) Kiran & Pran: Kila Siku, circa 1935-1955; 8624; 1 audio_recording 17.2 MB (Folder 297)
      Serial number: Young India, T 950, SR.152. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:15.
    - (Young India Band) Pardesi: Kugombana Kupatana, circa 1935-1955; 8635; 1 audio_recording 16.4 MB (Folder 298)
      Serial number: Young India, T 756, SR.133. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:05.
    - (Young India Band) Kiran & Varma: Kwaheri Tutaonana, circa 1935-1955; 8645; 1 audio_recording 16.3 MB (Folder 299)
      Serial number: Young India, T 953, SR.151. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:04.
    - (Young India Band) Varma: Mambo ni Mambo, circa 1935-1955; 8667; 1 audio_recording 17.1 MB (Folder 300)
      Serial number: Young India, T 951, SR.152. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:13.
    - (Young India Band) Manorma: Tangu Nalipokuona, circa 1935-1955; 8702; 1 audio_recording 16.9 MB (Folder 301)
      Serial number: Young India, T 952, SR.151. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:12.
    - (Young India Band) Miss Kiran & Pardesi: Nenda Zako, Nimechoke, circa 1935-1955; 8736; 1 audio_recording 14.9 MB (Folder 302)
      Serial number: Young India, T 753, SR.134. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:49.
    - (Young India Band) Sheela & Pardesi: Nimeona Sura Ya, circa 1935-1955; 8747; 1 audio_recording 16.9 MB (Folder 303)
      Serial number: Young India, T. 754, SR.133. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:11.
    - (Young India Band) Manorma & Varma: Picha Picha Yoko, circa 1935-1955; 8778; 1 audio_recording 14.8 MB (Folder 304)
      Serial number: Young India, T 954, SR.153. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:47.
    - (Young India Band) Pran: Sema Sasa, circa 1935-1955; 8785; 1 audio_recording 15.1 MB (Folder 305)
      Serial number: Young India, T 949, SR.153. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:50.
  - Young Novelty Club, 12501
    - Young Novelty Club: Bul Bul, circa 1955-1965; 8569; 1 audio_recording 15.7 MB (Folder 306)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.331, AB 662. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:57.
    - Young Novelty Club: Muhibu Sinihini, circa 1955-1965; 8717; 1 audio_recording 16.2 MB (Folder 307)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.331, AB 661. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:03.
    - Young Novelty Club: Bwaga Bwaga, circa 1955-1965; 8570; 1 audio_recording 14.4 MB (Folder 308)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.333, AB 665. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:43.
    - Young Novelty Club: Dawa Yangu, circa 1955-1965; 8586; 1 audio_recording 14.5 MB (Folder 309)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.333, AB 666. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:44.
  - Young Sports Musical Club, 12503
    - Young Sports Musical Club: Punguza Udhia, circa 1955-1965; 8782; 1 audio_recording 14.1 MB (Folder 310)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.478, AB.955. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:39.
    - Young Sports Musical Club: Salmia Mama, circa 1955-1965; 8784; 1 audio_recording 14.6 MB (Folder 311)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.478, AB.956. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:52.
  - Zakaria and Malikus, 12502
    - Zakaria & Malikus: Otiano, N/A; 8770; 1 audio_recording 15.4 MB (Folder 312)
      Serial number: Columbia, EOM.9, CES.10009. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Source of music is Yaseen and Party. Duration: 2:55.
    - Zakaria & Malikus: Oyango—Samba, N/A; 8771; 1 audio_recording 15.2 MB (Folder 313)
      Serial number: Columbia, EOM.9, CES.10010. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Source of music is Yaseen and Party. Duration: 2:52.
- Series II: Jamal Hafidh Jahadhmy collection, circa 1930-1975; 8536; 191 audio_recordings
  Series 2: Digital audio captured from audio cassette recordings of 78- and 45-r.p.m. records. These cassettes belong to Jamal Hafidh Jahadhmy, who created them by carefully transferring the audio recordings from records held in private collections in Mombasa, Kenya.
  - Abdulrahman Bin Karman, 12402
    - Abdulrahman Bin Karman: Atayul Habibata, 8889; 1 audio_recording 32.4 MB (Folder 314)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:03.
    - Abdulrahman Bin Karman: Halua Somali, N/A; 8917; 1 audio_recording 32.8 MB (Folder 315)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:06.
    - Abdulrahman Bin Karman: Ok Ashik-Somali, N/A; 9013; 1 audio_recording 35.4 MB (Folder 316)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:20.
    - Abdulrahman Bin Karman: Rauahu, 9021; 1 audio_recording 35.4 MB (Folder 317)
  - Alwattan Musical Club, 12403
    - Alwattan Musical Club: Hayana Ukomo, circa 1954-19555; 8608; 1 audio_recording 13.2 MB (Folder 318)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.2232, ABC.13815. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Leader: Sheikh Salim; Singer: Layla Maulidi. Duration: 2:29
    - Alwattan Musical Club: Ajabu ya Kuku, 1950; 8880; 1 audio_recording 15.8 MB (Folder 319)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:59.
    - Alwattan Musical Club: Akiba Mwenya Nayo, 1950; 8881; 1 audio_recording 15.0 MB (Folder 320)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:49.
    - Alwattan Musical Club: Ee, Baba Pakistan, 1950; 8910; 1 audio_recording 16.3 MB (Folder 321)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.1238, XYZ.680. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc Other notes: Leader: Subeti Salim Saidi. Duration: 3:04.
    - Alwattan Musical Club: Fundi Wangu Kanambiya, 1950; 8914; 1 audio_recording 14.2 MB (Folder 322)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:41.
    - Alwattan Musical Club: Illahi Wadudi, N/A; 8931; 1 audio_recording 14.8 MB (Folder 323)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:47.
    - Alwattan Musical Club: Iwapi Risala?, 1950; 8935; 1 audio_recording 14.4 MB (Folder 324)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.2246, ABC.13812. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:43.
    - Alwattan Musical Club: Kheri Unambiye, 8948; 1 audio_recording 12.5 MB (Folder 325)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:22.
    - Alwattan Musical Club: Machozi ya Huba, 1950; 8961; 1 audio_recording 15.6 MB (Folder 326)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:56.
    - Alwattan Musical Club: Mahaba Hatari, 1950; 8964; 1 audio_recording 15.0 MB (Folder 327)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:50.
    - Alwattan Musical Club: Mzishi Hazikwi, circa 1954-1955; 8981; 1 audio_recording 12.9 MB (Folder 328)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:26.
    - Alwattan Musical Club: Napenda Waeleza, 8992; 1 audio_recording 12.2 MB (Folder 329)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:18.
    - Alwattan Musical Club: Nikikwangalia, 1950; 9000; 1 audio_recording 14.7 MB (Folder 330)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:46.
      Swahili; Gallotone
    - Alwattan Musical Club: Tulizana Nikwambie, 1950; 9050; 1 audio_recording 14.6 MB (Folder 331)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:45.
  - Badi Rinda, 12404
    - Badi Rinda: Nakupa Batwini, 8989; 1 audio_recording 16.5 MB (Folder 332)
    - Badi Rinda: Tangu Kuepukana, 9041; 1 audio_recording 15.7 MB (Folder 333)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:57.
  - Banatil Wattan and Party, 12405
    - Banatil Wattan and Party: Kilele, 8953; 1 audio_recording 15.2 MB (Folder 334)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:52.
    - Banatil Wattan and Party: Samaki Akiosa, 9023; 1 audio_recording 15.2 MB (Folder 335)
  - Banusaada Lele-Mama, 12406
    - Banusaada Lele-Mama: Banusaada Tuko Uwanjani, N/A; 8891; 1 audio_recording 14.1 MB (Folder 336)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:39.
    - Banusaada Lele-Mama: Jaji Wetu Kwakutuma, N/A; 8936; 1 audio_recording 16.6 MB (Folder 337)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:08.
  - Black Star Musical Club, 12407
    - Black Star Musical Club, with Sharmila: Chozi Lanichoka, circa 1960-1972; 8900; 1 audio_recording 16.8 MB (Folder 338)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AL 485, HL 7-243. Original format: 45 rpm vinyl disc. Album label: An Assanand & Sons (Msa) LTD. Mzuri Recording. Location: Somalia. Duration: 3:10.
    - Black Star Musical Club, with Ursulla: Mpende Anae Kupenda, circa 1960-1972; 8977; 1 audio_recording 17.6 MB (Folder 339)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AL 486, HL 7-243. Original format: 45 rpm vinyl disc. Label: An Assanand & Sons (Msa) LTD. Mzuri Recording, mfd. by E. A. Records for Phonograph in E. Africa. Duration: 3:19.
    - Black Star Musical Club: Nilikupenda, circa 1960-1972; 9001; 1 audio_recording 16.5 MB (Folder 340)
      Serial number: Philips (Mzuri), AL 420, HL 7-210. Original format: 45 rpm vinyl disc. Label: An Assanand & Sons (Msa) LTD. Mzuri Recording, mfd. by E. A. Records for Phonograph in E. Africa. Duration: 3:06
    - Black Star Musical Club: Pili Pili, circa 1960-1972; 9017; 1 audio_recording 19.3 MB (Folder 341)
      Serial number: Philips, HL 7-210. Original format: 45 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:39.
  - Budda bin Mwendo, 12612
    - Budda Bin Mwendo: Basharaf Nadi Hijaz Huka, circa 1930; 8894; 1 audio_recording 30.3 MB (Folder 342)
      Serial number: Columbia, WE.25. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:51.
  - Budda Swedi, 12408
    - Budda Swedi: Jua Toka, N/A; 8939; 1 audio_recording 15.0 MB (Folder 343)
    - Budda Swedi: Sitambae 1, N/A; 9034; 1 audio_recording 14.6 MB (Folder 344)
    - Budda Swedi: Sitambae 2, N/A; 9035; 1 audio_recording 14.7 MB (Folder 345)
    - Budda Swedi: Taqsim-Oud, N/A; 9043; 1 audio_recording 32.9 MB (Folder 346)
    - Budda Swedi: Taqsim-Violin, N/A; 9044; 1 audio_recording 31.1 MB (Folder 347)
  - Egyptian Musical Club, 12409
    - Egyptian Musical Club: Nina Wingi Wa Furaha, 9005; 1 audio_recording 20.4 MB (Folder 348)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:51.
    - Egyptian Musical Club: Uzuri Huongezeka, N/A; 9058; 1 audio_recording 23.3 MB (Folder 349)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 4:24.
  - Hassan and Party, 12410
    - Hassan and Party: Mja Hulinda Kizima, 8976; 1 audio_recording 26.7 MB (Folder 350)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 5:03.
    - Hassan and Party: Ulimbaji wa Chooni, 9052; 1 audio_recording 24.3 MB (Folder 351)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 4:36.
  - Jauharah Orchestra, 12411
    - Jauharah Orchestra: Iwa Mtulivu, 1955; 8934; 1 audio_recording 14.0 MB (Folder 352)
      Original format: Trek, 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:38.
    - Jauharah Orchestra: Maashuki, 1952; 8960; 1 audio_recording 15.3 MB (Folder 353)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:53.
    - Jauharah Orchestra: Makusanya, N/A; 8967; 1 audio_recording 14.0 MB (Folder 354)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:38.
    - Jauharah Orchestra: Wakilindaje Kisima?, 1950; 9060; 1 audio_recording 15.9 MB (Folder 355)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.2229, ABC.13676. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:00.
    - Jauharah Orchestra: Wangu Ukhutina, 1955; 9061; 1 audio_recording 16.1 MB (Folder 356)
      Original format: Trek, 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:02.
  - Juma Bhalo and Party, 12412
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: Asma, N/A; 8888; 1 audio_recording 18.3 MB (Folder 357)
      Serial number: Mzuri (Philips), AL 299, HL 7-150. Original format: 45 rpm vinyl disc. Label: An Assanand & Sons (Msa) LTD. Mzuri Recording, mfd. by E. A. Records for Phonograph in E. Africa. Duration: 3:27.
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: Ghafula, N/A; 8916; 1 audio_recording 18.8 MB (Folder 358)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:33.
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: Howa Howa, circa 1960-1972; 8922; 1 audio_recording 17.4 MB (Folder 359)
      Serial number: Philips, HL 7-136. Original format: 45 rpm vinyl disc. Duration: 3:17.
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: Ila-Mahaba, N/A; 8929; 1 audio_recording 17.9 MB (Folder 360)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:23.
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: Kem Kem, N/A; 8947; 1 audio_recording 19.1 MB (Folder 361)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:36.
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: La La La La, 8959; 1 audio_recording 25.0 MB (Folder 362)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 4:43.
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: Mafuta, N/A; 8963; 1 audio_recording 19.1 MB (Folder 363)
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: Mpenzi Wenda Zako, N/A; 8711; 1 audio_recording 18.6 MB (Folder 364)
      Serial number: Mzuri (Philips), AL 300, HL 7-150. Original format: 45 rpm vinyl disc. Duration: 3:31.
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: Naliya, 8990; 1 audio_recording 19.1 MB (Folder 365)
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: Nenda, N/A; 8995; 1 audio_recording 18.8 MB (Folder 366)
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: Ni Uzito, N/A; 8998; 1 audio_recording 17.2 MB (Folder 367)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:14.
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: Niatani, N/A; 8999; 1 audio_recording 23.1 MB (Folder 368)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 4:22.
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: Nimechoka Kusubiri, circa 1960-1972; 9002; 1 audio_recording 17.5 MB (Folder 369)
      Serial number: Philips, HL 7-136. Original format: 45 rpm vinyl disc. Duration: 3:18.
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: Nntakusubiri, N/A; 9010; 1 audio_recording 19.0 MB (Folder 370)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:35.
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: Nuni, N/A; 9011; 1 audio_recording 16.1 MB (Folder 371)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:02.
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: Nyota, circa 1960-1972; 9012; 1 audio_recording 20.2 MB (Folder 372)
      Serial number: Philips, HL 7-181. Original format: 45 rpm vinyl disc. Duration: 3:20.
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: Pete, N/A; 9016; 1 audio_recording 17.6 MB (Folder 373)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:19.
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: Sende Zako, circa 1960-1972; 9028; 1 audio_recording 18.2 MB (Folder 374)
      Serial number: Philips, HL 7-181. Original format: 45 rpm vinyl disc. Duration: 3:26.
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: Si Mimi Ni Moyo, 9031; 1 audio_recording 18.5 MB (Folder 375)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:29.
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: Sina Neno, 9032; 1 audio_recording 20.1 MB (Folder 376)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:48.
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: Swahibu, N/A; 9037; 1 audio_recording 16.7 MB (Folder 377)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:09.
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: Tulia Utuwe, N/A; 9049; 1 audio_recording 22.6 MB (Folder 378)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 4:16.
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: Tuwe Mbali Mbali, N/A; 9051; 1 audio_recording 16.7 MB (Folder 379)
    - Juma Bhalo & Party: Usibadilike, N/A; 9056; 1 audio_recording 19.3 MB (Folder 380)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:38.
  - Juman Suleiman, 12413
    - Juma Suleiman: Dali Yawadudi, N/A; 8902; 1 audio_recording 17.5 MB (Folder 381)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:18.
    - Juma Suleiman: Nna Uwa Langu, 9008; 1 audio_recording 18.1 MB (Folder 382)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:25.
  - Maalim Shaban, 12415
    - Malim Shaban: Howa Howa Mwanangu, 8923; 1 audio_recording 15.3 MB (Folder 383)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Alternate spellings: Maalim Shaban, Maalim Shaaban, Mw. Shabaan. Duration: 2:53.
    - Malim Shaban: Kampanda Mla Mlelea, N/A; 8945; 1 audio_recording 15.6 MB (Folder 384)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Alternate spellings: Maalim Shaban, Maalim Shaaban, Mw. Shabaan. Duration: 2:56.
    - Malim Shaban: Kheri Uniambiye, N/A; 8949; 1 audio_recording 11.5 MB (Folder 385)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Alternate spellings: Maalim Shaban, Maalim Shaaban, Mw. Shabaan. Duration: 2:10.
    - Malim Shaban: Mahaba Jamani, N/A; 8965; 1 audio_recording 14.2 MB (Folder 386)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Alternate spellings: Maalim Shaban, Maalim Shaaban, Mw. Shabaan. Duration: 2:40.
    - Malim Shaban: Mbaazi, N/A; 8974; 1 audio_recording 15.2 MB (Folder 387)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Alternate spellings: Maalim Shaban, Maalim Shaaban, Mw. Shabaan. Duration: 2:52 MB.
    - Malim Shaban: Mbaazi 2, N/A; 8975; 1 audio_recording 15.2 MB (Folder 388)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Alternate spellings: Maalim Shaban, Maalim Shaaban, Mw. Shabaan. Duration: 2:52.
    - (Malim Shaban) and Siti Binti Saad and Group: Muhogo wa jang'ombe, circa 1930; 8980; 1 audio_recording 15.6 MB (Folder 389)
      Serial number: Columbia, WE.14, W 63049. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Alternate spellings: Maalim Shaban, Maalim Shaaban, Mw. Shabaan. Duration: 2:57.
    - Malim Shaban: Pemba, N/A; 9015; 1 audio_recording 12.6 MB (Folder 390)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Alternate spellings: Maalim Shaban, Maalim Shaaban, Mw. Shabaan. Duration: 2:22.
    - Malim Shaban: Uniombee Karima 1 and 2, circa 1930; 9055; 1 audio_recording 31.5 MB (Folder 391)
      Original format: Columbia, WE 21, 78 rpm shellac disc. Alternate spellings: Maalim Shaban, Maalim Shaaban, Mw. Shabaan. Duration: 5:57.
  - Malika, 12414
    - Malika: Africa, N/A; 8878; 1 audio_recording 26.0 MB (Folder 392)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Artist's full name: Asha Abdo Suleiman and was recorded when he was a Somali national and employee of the state. Duration: 4:55.
    - Malika: Africa [more complete version], N/A; 8879; 1 audio_recording 27.5 MB (Folder 393)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Artist's full name: Asha Abdo Suleiman and was recorded when he was a Somali national and employee of the state. Duration: 5:11.
    - Malika: Nimpendae Hajui, N/A; 9004; 1 audio_recording 26.7 MB (Folder 394)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Artist's full name: Asha Abdo Suleiman and was recorded when he was a Somali national and employee of the state. Duration: 26.7 MB.
  - Matano Juma, 12416
    - Matano Juma: Alfu Leila 1, N/A; 8883; 1 audio_recording 23.2 MB (Folder 395)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 4:23.
    - Matano Juma: Alfu Leila 2, N/A; 8884; 1 audio_recording 20.8 MB (Folder 396)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:56.
  - Mbaruk, 12417
    Alternate name
    Mbaruk Effendi
    - Mbaruk: Amma Baadu Nduyangu, N/A; 8885; 1 audio_recording 14.5 MB (Folder 397)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Alternate names of artist were Sheikh Mbaruk Effendi, Sheik Mbaruk Effendi, Mbaruk Effandi, Mbaruk Effendi, Mbaruk Talsam. Duration: 2:44.
    - Mbaruk: Basahera Umuongo, part 1, 1930; 8892; 1 audio_recording 30.3 MB (Folder 398)
      Original format: Odeon, A 24 21 52, Br.0.275, 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Alternate names of artist were Sheikh Mbaruk Effendi, Sheik Mbaruk Effendi, Mbaruk Effandi, Mbaruk Effendi, Mbaruk Talsam. Duration: 2:51.
    - Mbaruk: Basahera Umuongo, part 2, 1930; 8893; 1 audio_recording 30.5 MB (Folder 399)
      Original format: Odeon, Br.0.276, A 24 21 52, 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Alternate names of artist were Sheikh Mbaruk Effendi, Sheik Mbaruk Effendi, Mbaruk Effandi, Mbaruk Effendi, Mbaruk Talsam. Duration: 2:52.
    - Mbaruk: Bwana Swalehe, 8899; 1 audio_recording 29.8 MB (Folder 400)